We've just seen how to model our data if we assume that it is normally distributed.
我们刚刚学习了如何对正态分布的数据进行建模
But how do we decide if our data can be
但是如何判断数据
described by a normal distribution in the first place?
是否是正态分布呢？
A quick way to visually check,
一种快速直观的检验方式是
is to plot a histogram of our data.
绘制数据直方图
We can then compare the histogram to a plot of the normal distribution.
然后将该直方图与正态分布的图形进行比较
Does this data's distribution look normal?
这个数据的分布图看起来正态吗？
How about this one?
这个呢？
Does it look like we can still describe it with a normal distribution?
还能用正态分布描述它吗？
We can also use a boxplot to check for normality.
我们还可以使用盒形图检查正态性
As you'll soon see,
很快你会发现
the boxplot helps to check for symmetry in your data.
盒形图可以检查数据的对称性
Normal distributions are symmetric around their mean.
正态分布以均值对称
Here is a boxplot.
这是一个盒形图
There is a box with a line inside.
有一个盒子 里面有一条线
The bottom edge of the box,
盒子的底边
the middle line in the box,
盒子中间的线条
and the top edge of the box,
以及盒子的顶边
are quantiles that divide the data in two groups.
表示将数据分成两组的分位数
We call the dividing lines quantiles because
将分界线称为分位数是因为
they split the data into groups with the same number of points.
它们将数据拆分为具有相同数据点的小组
Since the three dividing lines create four groups,
因为三条分界线会形成四组
we call these lines quartiles.
所以我们将这些线称为四分位
Remember that the quartiles are the three dividing lines,
注意 四分位是三条分界线
not the four groups themselves.
不是四个小组本身
The line inside the box is the median.
盒子里面的线条是中位数
If you ordered all of your dataset from smallest to largest,
如果将数据集从小到大排序
50 percent of your data points are less than the median.
那么有 50% 的数据点小于中位数
The bottom side of the box represents the first quartile.
盒子的底边表示第一个四分位
Twenty five percent of the data are less than the first quartile.
25% 的数据小于第一个四分位
The top side of the box is the third quartile.
盒子的顶部是第三四分位
Seventy five percent of the data are less than the third quartile.
75% 的数据小于第三四分位
We can calculate the interquartile range by taking the third quartile,
四分位差等于第三四分位
minus the first quartile.
减去第一四分位
The boxplot has small lines on either end.
盒形图两端都有小短线
We call these lines whiskers.
称之为盒须
The lower bound whisker is defined as the first quartile,
下限盒须等于第一四分位
minus 1.5 times the interquartile range.
减去 1.5 倍四分位差
Similarly, the upper bound whisker is set to the third quartile,
同理 上限盒须等于
plus 1.5 times the interquartile range.
第三四分位加上 1.5 倍四分位差
Points lying outside of the whiskers can be considered
盒须之外的数据点被视作离群值
outliers and are visualized as individual points.
可以单独考虑
Going back to our test for normality,
回到正态性检验上
if you look at the normal distribution, it is symmetric.
观察正态分布后会发现它是对称的
When a distribution is symmetric,
当分布对称时
it's median is equal to it's mean.
中位数将等于均值
The first quartile and third quartile are also the same distance away from the median.
第一四分位和第三四分位离中位数的距离一样
Also, the whiskers are the same distance away from the median.
盒须离中位数的距离也一样
By visualizing your data with a boxplot,
用盒形图绘制数据
you can see whether it's symmetric or not.
可以看出数据是否对称
If it's not symmetric,
如果不对称
it's not normally distributed.
则不是正态分布
We can look at the data using both a box whisker plot and a histogram.
我们可以同时使用盒须图和直方图查看数据
Here, it looks like it follows a normal distribution.
此图看起来是正态分布
This other dataset is not normal.
这个数据集不是正态的
In fact, we say that it is skewed because it has
实际上 它是偏斜的
a long tail of data to only one side of the distribution.
因为只有一端有很长的尾巴
When there is a long tail of data to the left,
如果左侧有很长的尾巴
the mean of the distribution lies to the left of the median.
均值在中位数的左边
We say that the distribution is left skewed.
则分布是左偏斜
In fact, stock returns tend to exhibit left skew and fat tails.
实际上 股票往往是左偏斜 并且有肥尾
This means that extreme negative returns occur with
这表明极端负收益的发生频率
greater frequency than would be expected by a normal distribution.
比正态分布描绘的频率要高
Please note that even if your data is symmetric,
请注意 即使数据是对称的
it's not necessarily a bell-shaped curve of a normal distribution.
也不一定就是钟形正态分布曲线
So, it helps to see the box whisker plot,
所以有必要同时查看盒须图
as well as the histogram.
与直方图
To do a more thorough check for normality,
要更全面地检查正态性
we can use a QQ plot.
我们可以使用 QQ 图
The QQ plot checks if the shape of the data
QQ 图会检查数据的形状
matches the shape of our probability density function.
是否与此概率密度函数的形状一致
The first Q in QQ plot stands for quantile.
QQ 图中的第一个 Q 表示分位数
The second Q in QQ plot also stands for quantile.
第二个 Q 也表示分位数
Common quantiles are quartiles, deciles, and percentiles.
常见的分位数有四分位 十分位和百分位
Recall that when we sort the data points from smallest to largest,
如果将数据点从小到大排序
we can find boundaries that divide the data into groups with equal number of points.
我们可以按照一定的界限将数据分成若干等份
If we divide a data into 10 buckets,
如果将数据分成 10 等份
the nine boundaries are deciles.
9 个分界线称为十分位
If we divide the data into 100 buckets,
如果将数据分成 100 等份
the 99 boundaries are called percentiles.
99 个分界线称为百分位
Notice, that this is not the same as plotting a histogram.
注意 这与绘制直方图不同
With a histogram, the buckets have the same width.
对于直方图 分桶具有相同的宽度
With quantiles, the buckets all have the same number of data points.
对于分位数 分桶具有相同数量的数据点
QQ plots let us compare any two distributions to check if they have the same shape.
QQ 图可以比较任何两个分布图 看看它们是否形状一样
Since we want to check if a data is shaped like a normal distribution,
因为我们想检查数据的形状是否为正态分布
we can plot it's quantiles against the quantiles of a normal distribution.
所以可以将它的分位数与正态分布的分位数进行比较
As an example, let's take the 50th percentile of our data as our y-coordinate.
例如 我们可以将数据的第 50 百分位当做 y 轴坐标
Next, we take the 50th percentile of
然后将标准正态分布的
the standard normal distribution as our x-coordinate.
第 50 百分位当做 x 轴坐标
We plot this xy point on the QQ plot.
我们在 QQ 图上绘出此 (x,y) 点
We repeat this for all the other percentiles.
对所有其他百分位数都重复这一过程
If the two distributions have the same shape,
如果两个分布图的形状一样
then the plotted points will follow
那么绘制的点将呈一条直线
a straight line that goes from the bottom left to the top right.
从左下角延伸到右上角
In this QQ plot,
在此 QQ 图中
we can see that the data does not look like a normal distribution.
可以看出数据不像是正态分布
This is because the plotted points form a curve instead of a straight line.
这是因为这些点构成了曲线 而不是直线
So far, we've seen plots that help us visually check if our data looks like it's normal.
到目前为止 我们查看了可以直观检查数据是否正态的图形
What if we wanted a single number to represent how normal the data is?
如果我们想要用一个数字表示数据的正态性呢？
If we had a single number,
如果有一个数字
we could choose a cutoff point.
我们可以选择一个分界点
Anything on one side of this cutoff point,
在分界点一侧的所有数据点
and we decide that it's normal.
都是正态的
Anything on the other side of the cutoff point,
在分界点另一侧的所有数据点
and we decide that it's not normal.
都是非正态的
The Shapiro-Wilk test and the D'Augustino-Pearson tests,
Shapiro-Wilk 检验和 D'Augustino-Pearson 检验
are hypotheses tests that give a p-value.
是可以生成 p 值的假设检验
The p-value ranges from zero to one.
p 值的范围是 0-1
These are hypotheses tests in which
在这些假设检验中
the null hypothesis assumes that the data is normally distributed.
零假设认为数据是正态分布
If the p-value is larger than 0.05,
如果 p 值大于 0.05
then we will assume that it follows a normal distribution.
那么我们认为它是正态分布
If the p-value is less than 0.05,
如果 p 值小于 0.05
then it likely does not follow a normal distribution.
那么很可能不是正态分布
There is a another more general test to decide
还有一种更一般的检验
whether any two distributions are the same.
可以判断任何两个分布是否相同
This test is called the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test.
称为 Kolmogorov-Smirnov 检验
Given two distributions, the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test returns a p-value.
对于两个分布 Kolmogorov-Smirnov 检验将返回一个p 值
If the p-value is greater than 0.05,
如果 p 值大于 0.05
we will assume that the two distributions are the same.
那么我们认为这两个分布相同
If the p-value is less than 0.05,
如果 p 值小于 0.05
then we say the two distributions are not the same.
那么我们认为这两个分布不相同
Remember the reason why we care about the data being normal.
回忆下我们为何关心数据是否正态的原因
When we use statistical models such as regression,
当我们使用回归等统计学模型时
we use hypotheses tests to check if we can trust the model parameters of the model.
我们使用假设检验检查是否能信任模型的参数
These tests assume that our data is normally distributed.
这些检验假定数据是正态分布的
If the data are not normally distributed,
如果数据不是正态分布
these tests tend to tell us that our model is valid when in fact it is not.
这些检验往往会告诉我们模型是有效的 但实际上不是